Sean Homer



dev@sjhomer.com



linkedin.com/in/seanjhomer



4168540717



https://dev.sjhomer.com

Summary

As a leader in digital solutions, I have core competencies in Product and Project Management, Solution Architecture, Developer Management, and Development skills, with 17+ years in the digital space, with 12+ focused supporting digital agencies.

While starting in development, I've touched upon all aspects of working on digital products over the past two decades, to have the wherewithal to lead various roles across projects, while providing insights and guidance along the way to help deliver the best product.

The facets I undertake in my role:

- · Working to establish requirements, estimates, and high level architecture from RFPs
- Working to define a clear approach and ideal solution in establishing a project SoW
- · Working with client and team to help drive the product vision, solidify UX flows, adapt to changing scope, and ensure requirements are being adhered too in development
- Working to support, direct, and lead the development team from planning user and technical stories and tasks, drafting technical and system diagrams, establishing the code structure and standards and through code review ensure a level of consistent quality in code, managing code releases and deployments, and developing the more complex aspects or integrations on projects

In my personal time, I enjoy a wide range of hobbies and interests. I use meditation to help stay balanced and focus on my goals. I pursue creative endeavours through voice acting, writing, and music. I'm an avid fan of science fiction and fantasy, as well as roleplaying games.

Through working remotely, it has afforded my wife and I to live in a region we only dreamed of retiring in, and our next journey is building a tiny home with a homestead to live more sustainably.

It is my aim to continue helping companies strive to better company culture and processes, establish healthy working boundaries with clients and customers, and produce the best work possible while mitigating risks and stressors.

Experience



A Frontend Development Lead

Therefore Interactive | Digital Agency Apr 2019 - Present (3 years 2 months +)

- Decoupled E-commerce Solution Product Strategy Lead, UX Lead, Project Management Lead, Technical Strategy Lead, DevOps Lead, Development Lead. Aug 2021 May 2022
- Decoupled Crypto-currency Solution Product Strategy Lead, UX Lead, Project Management Lead, Technical Strategy Lead, API integrations, DevOps Lead, Development Lead. Sep 2020 Jul 2021
- Craft CMS Newsroom Product strategy, UX workflows, Project Management, Technical Strategy Lead, Development Lead, Quality Assurance May 2020 Sep 2020
- Decoupled E-Commerce Solution Product strategy, UX workflows, Project Management, Technical Strategy Lead, Lead API integrations, DevOps Lead, Development Lead, Mobile App Lead, Quality Assurance Apr 2019 - May 2020

Technical Architect

Therefore Interactive | Digital Agency

May 2018 - Apr 2019 (1 year)

- Working to transform the strategic processes, methods, and technical standards around front-end development and componentization within the company.
- Leading various projects from conception to completion, leveraging pull requests and code reviews to adhere to better standards.
- Enhancing the tooling and build processes to bring efficiencies to the team while working to decrease project complexity.
- Mentoring team members to enhance their hands-on skills for projects and development.

Senior Web Developer

Therefore Interactive | Digital Agency

Dec 2014 - May 2018 (3 years 6 months)

- Assisted in delivering an ecommerce SPA, making impactful contributions and improvements for a successful launch.
- Assisted and lead in the construction, agile management, UX, and compontentization of various marketing sites.
- Assisted in audtis to provide a solid UX for all devices, working with the designers to conceptualize mock ups, assist in user feedback testing, and applying the resulting changes to projects.
- Building and enhancing an automated testing suite for behaviour driven development.
- Leading research and development into tooling and libraries leveraging modern web components, testing, and work flow to bring the organization cutting edge solutions for new projects.

Web Developer

RC Design

Oct 2009 - Dec 2014 (5 years 3 months)

- Assisted in website conception, quotation, and design, while administrating all technical components on projects ranging from development, implementation, and configuration of analytics to SEO compliance.
- Led and developed three iterations of an in-house CMS framework that was used in client projects based on a MVC framework.
- Developed websites that leverage a series of handcrafted and customized jQuery plug-ins, and as well as other modular elements.
- Integrated ecommerce components that are specific to client needs in addition to providing a fluid user experience to shoppers.
- Designed and implemented productivity enhancements to the company's ERP system.

- Worked with other departments to ensure projects are tailored to client's specifications and are completed within deadlines.
- Participated in various team brainstorming sessions in order to yield the ideal results for new projects.

@

Web Developer

SteelSeries

Nov 2007 - Sep 2009 (1 year 11 months)

- Assisted in installing and configuring a revised webstore using the Magento framework, which included a customized layout and formatting to branding generated reports.
- Guided web initiatives from all aspects by executing and leading projects from creation through deployment.
- Administered and maintained web servers, which allowed consistent performance for the company's websites.
- Demonstrated ability as a team player in time-sensitive situations by assisting with numerous roles outside of the normal job requirements as a developer.



Intranet Web Developer

Ideazon

Jun 2006 - Nov 2007 (1 year 6 months)

- Handled the administration and development of the company's ERP system.
- Became familiar with the functionality of the system and addressed critical glitches that affected management's productivity during the abrupt departure of a former colleague.



QA Engineer

Ideazon

Apr 2005 - Jun 2006 (1 year 3 months)

- Researched and reported on competitor's hardware, news and trends in the gaming industry, and NDP sales data relating to game software in order to assist in our efforts in product and software development.
- Tested and debugged products and software, developing supporting software to implement functionality on our products, and modifying or creating documentation on improvement on QA processes.

Education



Seneca College

Computer Programming and Analysis, Computer Programming, Web Development 2001 - 2005

Skills

Team Leadership • Technical Architecture • Solution Architecture • Project Management • Agile Methodologies • React.js • GraphQL • Redux.js • Node.js • JavaScript